<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup on Micronaut MuShop</title>
    <link>/tags/setup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Setup on Micronaut MuShop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:28:12 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Oracle Cloud] Terraform &#43; Helm</title>
      <link>/quickstart/terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:28:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/terraform/</guid>
      <description>The terraform configuration scrips can be used to completely install MuShop to Oracle Cloud along with necessary Oracle Cloud Infrastructure services.
Prerequisites You need to install terraform locally.
Configuration Create copy of terraform variables file terraform.tfvars.example.
cp terraform.tfvars.example mushop.tfvars Then edit the mushop.tfvars:
  Configure the OCI authentication and deployment variables:
# OCI authenticationtenancy_ocid=&amp;#34;ocid1.tenancy.....&amp;#34;fingerprint=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;# e.g.: &amp;#34;5f:53:...&amp;#34; or leave blank if using CloudShelluser_ocid=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;# e.g.: &amp;#34;ocid1.user...&amp;#34; or leave blank if using CloudShellprivate_key_path=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;# e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Oracle Cloud] Helm</title>
      <link>/quickstart/helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 12:27:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/helm/</guid>
      <description>This deployment option utilizes helm for configuration and installation onto a Kubernetes cluster. It is recommended to use an Oracle Container Engine for Kubernetes cluster, however other standard Kubernetes clusters will also work.
cd deploy/complete/helm-chart dir deploy/complete/helm-chart  Path for Cloud Native deployment configurations using helm
 Deploying the complete MuShop application with backing services from Oracle Cloud Infrastructure involves the use of the following helm charts:
 setup: Installs umbrella chart dependencies on the cluster (optional) Not supported yet provision: Provisions OCI resources integrated with Service Broker (optional) mushop: Deploys the MuShop application runtime  To get started, create a namespace for the application and its associative deployments:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>