<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Micronaut MuShop</title>
    <link>/quickstart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Micronaut MuShop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 15:34:14 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[Local] Docker compose</title>
      <link>/quickstart/dockecompose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:28:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/dockecompose/</guid>
      <description>The complete Micronaut MuShop application can be run using docker-compose locally.
Default Configuration The default configuration that the docker-compose file uses is to be offline.
When using docker-compose some services are not available, such as publishing the newsletter which uses an Oracle Cloud Function, however the remaining services are functional.
Prerequisites You need Docker and Docker Compose installed locally and at least 8GB of resources assigned to Docker in order to run instances of Oracle database within containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Oracle Cloud] Terraform &#43; Helm</title>
      <link>/quickstart/terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 12:28:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/terraform/</guid>
      <description>The terraform configuration scripts can be used to completely install MuShop to Oracle Cloud along with necessary Oracle Cloud Infrastructure services.
Prerequisites You need to install terraform locally.
Configuration Create copy of terraform variables file terraform.tfvars.example.
cp terraform.tfvars.example mushop.tfvars Then edit the mushop.tfvars:
  Configure the OCI authentication and deployment variables. Follow the guidelines on how to obtain authentication details and configure the provider.:
# OCI authenticationtenancy_ocid=&amp;#34;ocid1.tenancy.....&amp;#34;fingerprint=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;# e.g.: &amp;#34;5f:53:...&amp;#34; or leave blank if using CloudShelluser_ocid=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;# e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Oracle Cloud] Resource manager</title>
      <link>/quickstart/oci-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 15:34:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/oci-terraform/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites You need to have an Oracle Cloud Infrastructure account.
Note that the charges will be applied since used services are not part of the Oracle Cloud Free Tier.
 Create stack To start with the OCI Resource Manager click on the following button:  
The link will redirect you to the Resource manager create stack page. Before the Resource manager will load the Terraform templates, you have to comply with Terms of Use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Oracle Cloud] Helm</title>
      <link>/quickstart/helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 12:27:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/helm/</guid>
      <description>This deployment option utilizes helm for configuration and installation onto a Kubernetes cluster. It is recommended to use an Oracle Container Engine for Kubernetes cluster, however other standard Kubernetes clusters will also work.
cd deploy/complete/helm-chart dir deploy/complete/helm-chart  Path for Cloud Native deployment configurations using helm
 Deploying the complete MuShop application with backing services from Oracle Cloud Infrastructure involves the use of the following helm charts:
 setup: Installs umbrella chart dependencies on the cluster (optional) Not supported yet provision: Provisions OCI resources integrated with Service Broker (optional) mushop: Deploys the MuShop application runtime  To get started, create a namespace for the application and its associative deployments:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[AWS] Cloudformation</title>
      <link>/quickstart/aws-cloudformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 15:34:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/aws-cloudformation/</guid>
      <description>Deploys complete Micronaut MuShop to Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) in combination with Amazon DocumentDb (with MongoDB compatibility), Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) and Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (MSK).
Prerequisites AWS account with configured billing.
Note that the charges will be applied since used services are not part of the AWS Free Tier.
 Create stack To start with the AWS Cloudformation click on the following button:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>